Guide to the Stanford University, Natural History Club, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Natural History Club, records
circa 1894-1959
SC0806
Stanford University. Natural History Club.
2.5 Linear feet (3 boxes)
Records include minutes, constitution, financial records, correspondence, photograph albums, and other miscellaneous materials. Of note are the bird list from a Baja California trip, 1940; undated field trip equipment list; and two pen and ink drawings by Prof. W. K. Fisher, one of which is the title page in the bound Zoology Club record book. The photograph albums document club field trips and natural history class groups; in most cases individuals are identified.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Parts of this collection were given to the Stanford University Archives by Mrs. John Thomas in 2004.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Zoology Club at Stanford University was founded by students in 1892; faculty and alumni were also welcomed as members. Field trips and lectures were the prominent activities. The club was reorganized in 1938 as the Stanford University Natural History Club, under the auspices of the Natural History Museum on campus.
Description of the Collection
Records include minutes, constitution, financial records, correspondence, photograph albums, and other miscellaneous materials. Of note are the bird list from a Baja California trip, 1940; undated field trip equipment list; and two pen and ink drawings by Prof. W. K. Fisher, one of which is the title page in the bound Zoology Club record book. The photograph albums document club field trips and natural history class groups; in most cases individuals are identified.
Access Terms
Fisher, Walter K., (Walter Kenrick), 1878-1953; Stanford University. Natural History Club.; Zoology Club (Stanford, Calif.).; Albums.; Biology--Fieldwork.
Collection Contents
- Zoology Club record book, circa 1894-1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Zoology Club record book: information on its binding (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minute book, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Treasurer's book, 1925-1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Treasurer's book, with some minutes, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bank records (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bird list, Baja California, 1940 Mar (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Constitution, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1923-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1952-1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Exhibit captions (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Field trip equipment list (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Financial records, 1930-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Map of club field trips, 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1947, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous records (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Notices of meetings (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Photographs (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Zoology Club sign by W. K. Fisher (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Loose photographs from [natural history] album, 1927, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Loose items from Zoology Club album (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Photograph album [natural history activities], 1906-1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Covers collecting trips, camping trips, local excursions, and specific class groups [black cloth cover].
- Photograph album of the Zoology/Natural History Club, circa 1894-1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Covers students and faculty on excursions (setting up camp, carrying gear, hiking, etc.) circa 1894-1923 and club trips to Pinnacles National Monument, Pacific Grove, lower California, Point Reyes, Moss Beach, Death Valley, Lake Kirkwood, Punta Penasco, and Borrego Valley, 1939-52 [leather cover].